<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insurance life IC - 02 on SATHEE</title>
    <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insurance life IC - 02 on SATHEE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/insurance-life-ic-02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 LIFE INSURANCE ORGANISATION Chapter Introduction </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-1-life-insurance-organisation-chapter-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-1-life-insurance-organisation-chapter-introduction/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1
LIFE INSURANCE ORGANISATION Chapter Introduction This chapter discusses how life insurance evolved; its organisational structure and functions. You will also learn about the appointment of life insurance agents, their duties and their remuneration. The chapter also takes you through the corridors of insurance history and acquaints you with the fascinating growth of this industry in India.
Learning Outcomes Overview of the Indian insurance market. Discuss about the activities and organisational structure of a life insurance company Learn about the appointment of life insurance agents and their functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insurance life</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/insurance-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/insurance-life/</guid>
      <description>LIFE INSURANCE
Life Insurance can be defined as a contract between an insurance policy holder and an insurance company, where the insurer promises to pay a sum of money in exchange for a premium, upon the death of an insured person or after a set period.
[Terminologies used in life insurance :]{.underline}
1. DOB
2. Tabaco
3. Occupation
4. Gender
5. Annual Income
6. Sum Assured
7. Coverage Till Age</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 2 PREMIUMS AND BONUSES
</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-2-premiums-and-bonuses-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-2-premiums-and-bonuses-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 2 PREMIUMS AND BONUSES Chapter Introduction Most insurance companies operate with the aim of earning profits and rewarding their policyholders and shareholders. The biggest worry for insurance companies is to maintain solvency i.e. income earned by the company should be enough to recover the cost of expenses and liabilities. If the income earned is more than the required amount to meet expenses and liabilities then the company is said to have earned profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 3 PLANS OF LIFE INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-3-plans-of-life-insurance-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-3-plans-of-life-insurance-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 3 PLANS OF LIFE INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In recent times, there have been drastic changes in the social structure we live in. There has been an increase in nuclear families, leaving the senior citizens alone, to manage on their own. Senior citizens today do not want to be dependent on their children for meeting their post retirement expenses. They want to be financially independent. With changed life styles, every parent aspires to provide the best of education to their children, without compromising on their life styles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 4 ANNUITIES </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-4-annuities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-4-annuities/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 4 ANNUITIES Chapter Introduction Retirement planning is an important tool for an individual, which helps them to be financially independent even after retirement. Government employees are more secure in this sense as they receive regular pension from their employers after retirement. But now-a-days, there is an increase in the workforce of people who are either self-employed or work in private companies that do not offer pensions to its employees. Hence the biggest worry for these individuals is to plan for their retirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 5 GROUP INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-5-group-insurance-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-5-group-insurance-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 5 GROUP INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In this competitive age, insurance companies are trying their level best to secure the highest client base. For this they try to come up with various innovative products to attract maximum customers towards them. They are also trying to expand their operations involving different customer segments. Corporate clients are one such customer segment that is being targeted by insurance companies. Corporate clients in turn, are trying to outsource their various activities to specialists in the fields (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 6 LINKED LIFE INSURANCE POLICIES </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-6-linked-life-insurance-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-6-linked-life-insurance-policies/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 6 LINKED LIFE INSURANCE POLICIES Chapter Introduction ULIPs gained a lot of popularity among investors during the bull run of Indian stock markets from 2003 to 2007. During this time period, the BSE Sensex rose from 3000 points to 20,000 points. With the BSE index multiplying six times over this five year period, the interest of investors in the capital markets was very high. So keeping in mind the requirements of the investors, insurance companies came up with various ULIP products and their variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 7 APPLICATION AND ACCEPTANCE
</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-7-application-and-acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-7-application-and-acceptance/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 7 APPLICATION AND ACCEPTANCE Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you with an understanding of the processes involved for both the proposer and the insurer when applying for a life insurance policy and its acceptance. It explains the importance of utmost good faith for insurance contracts, the essentials of an insurance contract and insurable interest. It also aims to provide an understanding of the importance of the role of underwriting and the process insurers use to assess risk and underwrite a proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 8 POLICY DOCUMENTS
</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-8-policy-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-8-policy-documents/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 8 POLICY DOCUMENTS Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you with an understanding of the importance of the insurance document. Each different section of the policy document has a different purpose and it is important to be able to understand the sections and their purposes.
Learning Outcomes Understand the importance of the policy document and the information contained in it.
Look at this scenario Parties enter into agreements, and details relating to these agreements are documented in what is known as a contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 9 PREMIUM PAYMENT, POLICY LAPSE AND REVIVAL

</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-9-premium-payment-policy-lapse-and-revival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-9-premium-payment-policy-lapse-and-revival/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 9 PREMIUM PAYMENT, POLICY LAPSE AND REVIVAL An Introductory Overview Lifeinsurance is an agreement that assures payment of a stated amount of money at the end of a specified term or on the death of the life insured if the client keeps his promise of paying his premium in time. It provides for financial security in the event of death or on the inability to earn due to physical disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 10 ASSIGNMENT, NOMINATION AND SURRENDER OF POLICY
</title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-10-assignment-nomination-and-surrender-of-policy-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/chapter-10-assignment-nomination-and-surrender-of-policy-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 10 ASSIGNMENT, NOMINATION AND SURRENDER OF POLICY Chapter Introduction Insurance companies have diversified, and introduced insurance products that can cater to each and every financial need of an individual. When an individual invests in an insurance policy they are actually investing in a long term asset. This asset not only provides insurance cover and returns on the investment, but can also be used to avail loan in times of financial crunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 11 POLICY CLAIMS </title>
      <link>/insurance-life-ic-02/policy-claims-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-life-ic-02/policy-claims-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 11 POLICY CLAIMS Chapter Introduction This chapter explains the different aspects of policy claims. After going through the chapter, you will get a clear picture of various kinds of policy claims and insurance riders etc.
Learning Outcomes Explain policy claims and their different types. Discuss the types of death claims: early claims and non-early claims. Learn about proof of title of claimant, claim concession and presumption of death. Understand Accidental Death Benefit, Permanent Disability Benefit and post maturity options.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
