<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insurance Health IC - 27 on SATHEE</title>
    <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insurance Health IC - 27 on SATHEE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/insurance-health-ic-27/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>INTRODUCTION TO HEALTH INSURANCE AND THE HEALTH SYSTEM IN INDIA
</title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-1-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-1-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1 INTRODUCTION TO HEALTH INSURANCE AND THE HEALTH SYSTEM IN INDIA Chapter Introduction This chapter provides you with the brief introduction about the meaning of health insurance and its purpose. It discusses about the development and growth of the insurance industry in India. You will also get an insight into the health system and health infrastructure of India at all the levels. This all will further help you to understand about the operation of the health insurance system in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH FINANCING MODELS AND HEALTH FINANCING IN INDIA </title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-2-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-2-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 2 HEALTH FINANCING MODELS AND HEALTH FINANCING IN INDIA Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you knowledge about how the financing of healthcare needs is done in any country. It will also discuss the health financing models of some of the countries, which will help to understand the characteristics, advantages and disadvantages of each method of healthcare financing. Lastly, this chapter explains the health financing model of our country and its drawbacks in terms of access and quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH INSURANCE PRODUCTS IN INDIA </title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-3-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-3-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 3 HEALTH INSURANCE PRODUCTS IN INDIA Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide knowledge about the most common and popular insurance products available in the Indian market and the coverage and characteristics of each of these products. We will also discuss the new innovative health insurance products coming up in the Indian market.
Learning Outcomes A. Attributes of Indian health insurance products B. Innovative health insurance products in India</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH INSURANCE UNDERWRITING </title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-4-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-4-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 4 HEALTH INSURANCE UNDERWRITING Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you detailed knowledge about underwriting in health insurance. Underwriting is a very important aspect of any type of insurance and plays an important factor in issuance of an insurance policy. In this chapter, you will get an understanding about basic principles, tools, methods and process of underwriting. It will also provide you the knowledge about group health insurance underwriting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH INSURANCE POLICY FORMS AND CLAUSES </title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-5-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-5-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 5 HEALTH INSURANCE POLICY FORMS AND CLAUSES Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you with an understanding of health insurance contract, proposal forms used for various health insurance products. You will also learn about common and standard clauses in an insurance contract, common nomenclature and definitions for some of the critical illnesses such as cancer, heart attack etc.
Learning Outcomes A. Health insurance contract B. Health insurance proposal form C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH INSURANCE DATA, PRICING AND RESERVING
</title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-6-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-6-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 6 HEALTH INSURANCE DATA, PRICING AND RESERVING Chapter Introduction This chapter aims to provide you with knowledge about importance of data for health insurance, various sources of data for health insurance and how is it collected and analysed for various purposes. It will also brief you about the IRDA&amp;rsquo;s role in collecting, processing and disseminating the health insurance data. It will also discuss the actuarial role and techniques for pricing and reserving in health insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REGULATORY AND LEGAL ASPECTS OF HEALTH INSURANCE
</title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-7-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-7-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 7 REGULATORY AND LEGAL ASPECTS OF HEALTH INSURANCE Chapter Introduction Insurance is promise sold to the customer. In order to maintain the trust of people, it is imperative that the insurer honours the promise. A variety of risks such as insurance risk, invesrment risk or liquidity risk endanger the fullfillment of this promise. Self-regulation can protect the insurer against these risks. However an independent regulatory body is needed to add an extra degree of control on the insurance business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUSTOMER SERVICE IN HEALTH INSURANCE
</title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-8-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-8-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 8 CUSTOMER SERVICE IN HEALTH INSURANCE Chapter introduction The chapter discusses how the consumer (policyholder) protection can be achieved and lists various channels where consumer can register their complaints relating to personal insurance claims.
Learning Outcomes A. Consumer protection B. Claim servicing C. Grievance redressal
A. Consumer protection Effective policyholder protection is one of the most important components of a sound and competitive insurance market. Where this is lacking, prospects and policyholders could be exposed to unfair practices by insurers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH INSURANCE FRAUD
</title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-9-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-9-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 9 HEALTH INSURANCE FRAUD Chapter introduction The chapter introduces you to the insurance frauds in healthcare sector. It discusses the causes and effects of fraud along with its classification. It also deals with the methods to combat health insurance fraud and IRDA&amp;rsquo;s initiative to create fraud database.
Learning Outcomes A. Frauds B. Perception cum causes and effects of fraud C. Health insurance frauds vs. General insurance frauds D. Consumer frauds E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REINSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-10-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-health-ic-27/chapter-10-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 10 REINSURANCE Chapter Introduction The chapter explains the concept and utility of reinsurance in health insurance. Reinsurance is insurance for insurance companies.
Learning Outcomes A. Introduction to reinsurance B. Utility of reinsurance C. Health insurance and reinsurance models D. Niche products supported by reinsurers E. Criteria used to decide on reinsurance programs
Look at this Scenario Reinsurance protects a primary insurer from catastrophic losses and allows insurers to better predict and manage their risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
