<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insurance Motor IC - 72 on SATHEE</title>
    <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insurance Motor IC - 72 on SATHEE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/insurance-motor-ic-72/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1 INTRODUCTION TO MOTOR INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/introduction-to-motor-insurance-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/introduction-to-motor-insurance-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1 INTRODUCTION TO MOTOR INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will know about the history of Motor Insurance and the principles of insurance contracts applicable to Motor Insurance. You will also learn about the legal aspects of insurance including various definitions, role of permit, licensing provisions and the key issues of Motor Vehicles (Amendment) Bill, 2008.
Learning Outcomes A. History of Motor Insurance and Principles of Insurance Contracts applicable to Motor Insurance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Insurance Session 1</title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-1/</guid>
      <description>﻿
Motor Insurance Training - Session 1 • By - vikas.sharma@renewbuy.com
Rules Undivided focus
“Right knowledge is the ultimate solution to all our problems.” - Bhagavad Gita
Overview ● What is Motor Insurance
● Types of Motor Insurance
● Components of the Premium
● RB tech platform and Motor Insurance
What is Motor Insurance ● A safety cover for your vehicle
● Mandatory - Motor Vehicle Act 1988
● Regulator - IRDAI (Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 2 MARKETING IN MOTOR INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/marketing-in-motor-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/marketing-in-motor-insurance/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 2 MARKETING IN MOTOR INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about declined risk pool, knock for knock agreement, international issues in motor insurance market and some Indian market practices like motor insurance online, role of dealers, manufacturers and garages and pay as you drive, drive less pay less and rent a car.
Learning Outcomes A. Motor Third Party Pool B. Knock for Knock Agreement and some Market Practices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Insurance Session 2</title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-2/</guid>
      <description>Motor Insurance Training - Session 2 • By - vikas.sharma@renewbuy.com
Overview
● Understanding the motor insurance dictionary
Terminologies at Quotes Page 1. Vehicle Model
2. Registered RTO
3. Purchase Date
4. Previous Insurer
5. IDV (Insured Declared Value)
6. Passenger Cover
7. PA Owner Driver Cover
8. TPPD Restricted
Terminologies at Quotes Page 11. Paid Driver Cover
12. Company owned vehicle ?
13. Ownership transfer
14. Insurance claimed this year ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 3 TYPE OF MOTOR VEHICLES, DOCUMENTS AND POLICIES </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/type-of-motor-vehicles-documents-and-policies-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/type-of-motor-vehicles-documents-and-policies-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 3 TYPE OF MOTOR VEHICLES, DOCUMENTS AND POLICIES Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the types of Motor Vehicles and various documents like proposal form, certificate of insurance, cover note, and policy forms used in Motor Insurance. The chapter also covers types of Motor Policies, Liability Cover under Package Policies, coverage for various vehicles, Motor Trade Policies, Scope of Motor Trade Internal Risks Policies, New technologies in cars and in auto field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Insurance Session 3</title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-3/</guid>
      <description>Motor Insurance Training - Session 3 • By - vikas.sharma@renewbuy.com
Overview ● Understanding the motor insurance dictionary
Terminologies at Quotes Page 1. Vehicle Model
2. Registered RTO
3. Purchase Date
4. Previous Insurer
5. IDV (Insured Declared Value)
6. Passenger Cover
7. PA Owner Driver Cover
8. TPPD Restricted
11. Paid Driver Cover
12. Company owned vehicle ?
13. Ownership transfer
14. Insurance claimed this year ?
15. Existing NCB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 4 UNDERWRITING IN MOTOR INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/underwriting-in-motor-insurance-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/underwriting-in-motor-insurance-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 4 UNDERWRITING IN MOTOR INSURANCE Chapter Introduction The chapter covers market practice of motor insurance in India; guidelines applicable in India; amendments subsequent to discontinuance of Tariff; international practice in motor insurance; underwriting criteria, principles and practice of premium computation; motor underwriting &amp;ndash; key to the health of the industry including data collection, developing underwriting scores methodology and its impact on motor insurance profitability.
Learning Outcomes A. Market practice of Motor Insurance in India B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 5 MOTOR INSURANCE CLAIMS </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-claims-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-claims-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 5 MOTOR INSURANCE CLAIMS Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the concept of motor insurance claims, motor claims work-flow procedures and type of losses. You will also learn about the role of the Surveyor in general and his role in loss minimisation in motor insurance. Towards the end of the chapter we will focus on the role of road safety in insurance by insurance industry and frauds in motor own damage claims and ways to mitigate frauds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 6 IT APPLICATIONS IN MOTOR INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/it-applications-in-motor-insurance-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/it-applications-in-motor-insurance-1/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 6 IT APPLICATIONS IN MOTOR INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the importance of analytics and IT intervention, including predictive analytics in claims. The chapter also covers need for and importance of statistics, TAC as data depository, TAC as National Repository for statistical data and future of auto insurance.
Learning Outcomes A. Importance of Analytics and IT intervention B. Need for and Importance of Statistics C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 7 CONSUMER DELIGHT </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/consumer-delight-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/consumer-delight-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 7 CONSUMER DELIGHT Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the evolution of the quality service concept and the basic elements of customer service. The chapter also discusses the regulatory, statutory, self and internal commitments. In the end the chapter explores the service gaps in motor claims and related customer experience management.
Learning Outcomes A. Evolution of Quality Service Concept and Basic Elements of Customer Service B. Service Gaps in Claims and Customer Experience Management</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 8 THIRD PARTY LIABILITY INSURANCE </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/third-party-liability-insurance-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/third-party-liability-insurance-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 8 THIRD PARTY LIABILITY INSURANCE Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the international legal scenario, purport of the Third Party claims management in India. We will also explore persons who can claim compensation, jurisdiction of Civil Courts and the alternative methods of settlement. Towards the end of the chapter we will understand the principles of damages, quantification and assessment of compensation; besides limited defenses available to insurer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 9 PROCEDURES FOR FILING AND DEFENDING </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/procedures-for-filing-and-defending-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/procedures-for-filing-and-defending-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 9 PROCEDURES FOR FILING AND DEFENDING Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about the procedures and powers of claims tribunals, procedure for filing and defending third party claims and steps to be taken in third party motor accident cases.
Learning Outcomes A. Legal Provisions and Jurisdiction of Civil Courts B. Procedure for Filing &amp;amp; Defending and Steps for Third Party Motor Accident Cases
A. Legal Provisions and Jurisdiction of Civil Courts Procedures and Powers of Claims Tribunals Section 169 (1) of Motor Vehicle Act 1988 stipulates that the Tribunal can in the exercise of own decision grant adjournment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 10 QUANTUM FIXATION </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/quantum-fixation-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/quantum-fixation-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 10 QUANTUM FIXATION Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about assessment of compensation, permissible heads, damage to third party property, option to choose jurisdiction, some case studies for damages to non-earning members and treatment of interest.
Learning Outcomes A. Assessment of Compensation and Type of Damages B. Option to choose Jurisdiction C. Some Case Studies for Damages to Non-earning Members
A. Assessment of Compensation and Type of Damages Assessment of Compensation The purpose of granting damages in pecuniary termsunder the Motor Vehicle Act, 1988 is to provide to the dependents of the victim of motor accident a capital sum, if there had not been an accident by the careless act of the driver of a motor vehicle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 11 FRAUD MANAGEMENT AND INTERNAL AUDIT </title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/fraud-management-and-internal-audit-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/fraud-management-and-internal-audit-/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 11 FRAUD MANAGEMENT AND INTERNAL AUDIT Chapter Introduction In this chapter you will learn about frauds in TP claims and frauds in Motor Insurance. You will also know about the types of frauds, how to underwrite frauds and the issues to be audited.
Learning Outcomes A. Frauds in TP Claims and Frauds in Motor Insurance B. Underwriting Frauds and Issues to be audited
A. Frauds in TP Claims and Frauds in Motor Insurance Frauds in TP Claims Third Party claims settlements are a drag on an insurer&amp;rsquo;s profitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Insurance Session 4</title>
      <link>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/insurance-motor-ic-72/motor-insurance-training-session-4/</guid>
      <description>Motor Insurance Training - Session 4 • By - vikas.sharma@renewbuy.com
Overview ● Adaptor
What is Adaptor 1. A folder where code an insurer is written
2. Three types of adaptors
a. Comprehensive - renewbuy/integrations/motor
b. SAOD - renewbuy/integrations/odonly
c. SATP - renewbuy/integrations/tponly
Let’s dive into Comprehensive - Structure 1. Imports
2. Define the Class - inherit SoapAdaptor (if it is Soap request)
3. Methods
a. __init__
b. get_quote
c. create_proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
