<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to become a better programmer on SATHEE</title>
    <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to become a better programmer on SATHEE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title> Be a Curious Cat 🐱 </title>
      <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point1/</guid>
      <description>Be a Curious Cat 🐱 Always ask questions and learn new things! The more we know, the better we can solve problems and create cool stuff. So, keep exploring and never be afraid to ask, &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;
Here&amp;rsquo;s why asking questions is important: It helps you uncover the challenges you&amp;rsquo;re facing and generate better solutions to solve those problems. We&amp;rsquo;re all spending too much time and energy solving the first iteration of a challenge with the first idea we have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Be a Broken Record 🔁 </title>
      <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point2/</guid>
      <description>Be a Broken Record 🔁 Remember how mommy or daddy repeats themselves when teaching you something new? It&amp;rsquo;s because practice makes perfect! As a programmer, we should practice too. Do things many times and learn from our mistakes to become better.
Here are some points elaborating on the importance of practice for programmers: Practice builds expertise: Just like in any other profession, practice makes perfect for programmers too.
The more a programmer practices, the more comfortable and proficient they become in their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a Superhero with X-ray Vision 👓 </title>
      <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point3/</guid>
      <description>Be a Superhero with X-ray Vision 👓 Superheroes can see through walls, right? We should be able to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; inside our computer programs and understand how they work. This way, we can fix problems and make them better!
Here are some points: Understanding how computer programs work is important for software developers to identify and fix problems, optimize performance, and add new features.
Debuggers and logging are two techniques that can help developers &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; inside their programs and gain insight into their workings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a Master Builder 🏗️ </title>
      <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point4/</guid>
      <description>Be a Master Builder 🏗️ Imagine building a giant LEGO tower. Would you use random pieces or follow a plan? A good programmer makes a plan before writing code. This helps us build strong and stable programs, just like our LEGO tower!
Here are some points to remember: A good programmer always makes a plan before writing code.
This planning process helps in building strong and stable programs.
Planning before writing code helps to identify potential issues and streamline the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a Gardener 🌻 </title>
      <link>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-become-a-better-programmer/point5/</guid>
      <description>Be a Gardener 🌻 Taking care of a garden is a lot of work. We need to water the plants, remove weeds, and keep it neat. The same goes for our programs! We should keep them clean and well-organized so they grow strong and healthy.
Why You Should Write Clean Code There are a variety of benefits to writing clean code. Some of them include the following:
Problems become easier to solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
